Guide to the Engin Ozendes Collection of Ottoman photography AD.MC.012
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
Engin Ozendes Collection
1900-1920
1890-1920
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
Ozendes, Engin, Ms.
Studio - G. Glikeas (Glykias), Phener Rue Balat, Sokak Apti Sou-Bashi no 15, Constantiople (Balat, Fatih, Istanbul, Turkey)
Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey)
Akozer, Ali Sami
American Colony, Jerusalem
Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890)
Berggren, Guillaume
Bonfils, Felix
Comtesse de Croix-Mesnil
D. Michailides, Andrinople (Edirne, Turkey)
Iranian, Mihran, Active circa 1890-1900
J. Gamlier, Grande Rue du Vardor 17 (Thessaloniki, Greece)
Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet
Luigi, Fiorillo
Osmanli Fotografhanesi, Skopje (Macedonia)
Othmar, Pferschy
Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey)
Pokoriya, Odessa (Ukraine)
Rahmizade, Bahaeddin, Mr
Raphael Khendamian (Kadikoy, Istanbul, Turkey)
Rubellin, Rue Franque, Passage Psaro-Khan, Smyrne (Iznir, Turkey)
Samanci, Asil
Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey)
Studio - Anastasios Sklavounos, photorapher (ΑΝΑΣΤΑΣΙΟΣ ΣΚΛΑΒΟΥΝΟΣ. ΦΩΤΟΓΡΑΦΟΣ)
Studio - Constantinides, Place du Tunnel 517, Pera (Istanbul, Turkey)
Studio - Jean Weinberg, Pera-Constantinople (Istanbul, Turkey)
Studio - Photo Resna, Stamboul (Istanbul, Turkey)
Studio - Photo Simon, 414 Grande Rue Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey)
Studio - Photographie Moriglioni, Bursa (Turkey)
Studio - Yeni Dunya Fotografhanesi, Galata Topcilar Caddesi No. 230 (Istanbul, Turkey)
Studio Atelier F. Stoklas, Baden, Neugasse 57 (Germany)
Studio August Töke, Photografie-Atelier, Bruck an der Leitha, filiale im K.U.K. Militar-Lager (Austria)
Studio B. Kargopoulo & Foscolo, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey)
Studio Basile Kargopoulo Photographe, Place du Tunnel No. 4, Pera, Constantinople (Succursale à Andrinople (Edirne)) (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey)
Studio Carlo Bukmedjian, Rue des Roses 7, Izmir (Turkey)
Studio Derounian Freres, Alep, Syrie (Aleppo, Syria)
Studio Disderi, 8 Boulevard des Italiens (Paris, France)
Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout (Lebanon)
Studio Foto Hilal, Bakirkoy, Istanbul Cad Cavusoglu pasaji 9 (Turkey)
Studio Fotografhane-i Osmani ve Aflam, Besiktas (Istanbul, Turkey)
Studio Fr. Marutzky, Neuchatel, Switzerland
Studio G. Lekegian & Co, Opposite Shepheard's Hotel, Esbekieh, Cairo (Egypt)
Studio G. Wunsch, Vienna, Austria
Studio L. Angerer, Vienna, Austria
Studio Pantoykian
Studio Parnasse, Constantinople (Istanbul, Turkey)
Studio Paul Tarkoul, Phebus, Constantinople
Studio Phebus, Grand Rue de Pera No. 301, au-deasus de la Maison Flament, Constantinople (Istanbul, Turkey)
Studio Photo Abel, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey)
Studio Photo L'Aigle, Grand Rue de Pera 429, Constantinople (Istanbul, Turkey)
Studio Photo Varjabedian, Zagazig, Egypt
Studio Photographie Parisienne, Izmir, Turkey
Studio Window & Grove, London, England
Tolgay, Hayri T.
Turkkan, Omer Fahreddin
Unknown
Y. Nalbandian, Photographe
Z.G. Donatosian (Baghdad, Iraq)
Zangaki Brothers
AD.MC.012
5 paige_boxes
Scope and Contents
The Engin Ozendes collection includes 315 iconic photographs taken by some of the most prominent photographers and photography studios who documented the last days of the Ottoman Empire and the early Republic period, including Abdullah Freres, Basile Kargapoulo, Zangaki, Sebah & Joaillier, Pascal Sebah, Derounian Freres, Othmar Pferschy, M. Iranian, Berggren, and Arif Hikmet Koyunoglu. The majority of the photographs, all of which are prints, date from the 1890s to 1910s.
The collection's studio photographs, from various places within the boundaries of modern-day Turkey, Syria, Iraq, Lebanon, Egypt, Greece, Palestine and Israel, present people as everything from simply children and parents, brides and grooms, to prominent military, religious and political figures. Historically significant moments related to both cultural events and military campaigns are represented as well as candid views of street life in cities and towns. The collection depicts the art and architecture from mosques and other religious and archaeological sites from throughout the region, revealing details that in some cases no longer exist, or exist in a different form today.
Arrangement
The collection was processed as it was received.
Conditions Governing Access
Digitization of this collection was completed in April 2016.
Custodial History
Akkasah, the Center for Photography at NYU Abu Dhabi, acquired the collection in December 2015.
Biographical / Historical
Engin Ozendes began researching the history of Turkish photography in 1974. Her articles on this subject have been published in numerous newspapers, magazines and encyclopedias. She has served as a jury member for many photographic competitions, and delivered lectures. In 1990 she was awarded the title Excellence Fiap (ESFIAP) by the Federation Internationale de L'Art Photographique (FIAP) for her services to photography. Between June 2004 - May 2011 she worked as Curator of Photography Exhibitions at Istanbul Museum of Modern Art. She curated many photography exhibitions internationally. Her books include Photography in the Ottoman Empire 1839-1919 (Haset Publications, 1987), Photography in the Ottoman Empire 1839-1919 (Iletisim, 1995), Abdullah Freres: Ottoman Court Photographers (Yapi Kredi. 1998), From Sebah & Joaillier to Foto Sabah: Orientalism in Photography (Yapi Kredi, 1999), Photography in Turkey (Tarih Vakfi, 1999), Merhaba Atina Here Istanbul (Tarih Vakfi, 2000), Photography in the Ottoman Empire 1839-1923 (Yapi Endustri, 2013), Modern and Contemporary Approaches to Photography in Turkey (Yapi Endustri, 2016).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection acquired from photo historian Engin Ozendes in 2015.
Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Ottoman Writing; Turkey; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Egypt; Syria
- Boy in a dark jacket, leaning on a carved wood banister. 10.6 x 6.7 cm, 1889; 3460; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Painted Backdrops; Boys; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Albumen Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Furnishings; Constantinople; Children; Boys
- Man with a mustache and beard in a three-piece suit with a hat and a pin below his collar. Same man from ref3. 10.7 x 6.3 cm, 1888; 3461; Studio Atelier F. Stoklas, Baden, Neugasse 57 (Germany) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Studio Photography; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Individual Portraits; Baden, Germany; Fezes/Tarbouches; Hats; Men; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair
- Man in a three-piece, wearing a fez and a pin below the center of his collar. 10.7 x 6.4 cm, 1888; 3462; Studio Atelier F. Stoklas, Baden, Neugasse 57 (Germany) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Baden, Germany; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Fezes/Tarbouches; Men; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair
- Seroupe Takvoryan in a three-piece suit with a striped tie. 10.4 x 6.4 cm, Undated; 3463; Studio Fr. Marutzky, Neuchatel, Switzerland (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Fezes/Tarbouches; Men; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; French Writing; Individual Portraits; Neuchatel, Switzerland; Facial Hair
- Tahsin, holding sword. 10.8 x 6.8 cm, 21 Aralık 1909; 3465; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Ottoman Writing; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Swords/Knives; Individual Portraits; Weapons; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Men; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Fezes/Tarbouches; Facial Hair
- Mehmet Pasha. 10.4 x 6.4 cm, 29 Temmuz 1913; 3466; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Individual Portraits; Turkey; Pasha; Ottoman Writing; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Hats; Uniforms; Facial Hair; Men; Military/Soldiers
- Woman in dress with her right hand resting on a wooden pedestal. 10.9 x 6.9 cm, June 1892; 3467; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Women; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Armenian Writing; Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops
- Therese Honegger as baby girl, sitting on a chair. Subject also in ref51 and ref69. 10.5 x 6.3 cm., 1860s; 3468; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Furnishings; Constantinople; Girls; Individual Portraits; Children; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card
- Portrait of Sinasi Sadun on a motorcycle. 6.8 x 9.3 cm, 30 March 1924; 3469; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Photographic Prints; Men; Individual Portraits; Ottoman Writing; Hats; Motorcycles; Turkey; Albumen Prints; Transportation; Fezes/Tarbouches
- Two bell ringers at the Surp Kevork Armenian church in Samatya, Istanbul. 12.2 x 8.1 cm, Undated; 3470; Victoria Portrait (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Turkish Writing; Hats; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Churches; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Religious Sites; Facial Hair; Fezes/Tarbouches
- Second Lieutenant Nuri. Presented to Seyit Habibullah Efendi in mark of his affection. 18 x 10.8 cm, 13 October 1913; 3471; Studio Fotografhane-i Osmani ve Aflam, Besiktas (Istanbul, Turkey); Sakib, Ali (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Painted Backdrops; Weapons; Individual Portraits; Ottoman Writing; Skopje, Macedonia; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Swords/Knives; Hats; Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Fezes/Tarbouches
- Haldun, aged 2, wearing a nautical outfit. 16.5 x 10.6 cm, 7 June 1895; 3472; Studio - Photographie Moriglioni, Bursa (Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Bursa, Turkey; Ottoman Writing; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Children; Boys; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; French Writing; Greek Writing; Painted Backdrops; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Maritime/Nautical Outfits
- Haldun, aged 2, in dark outfit standing. 16.5 x 10.6 cm, 7 November 1894; 3473; Studio - Photographie Moriglioni, Bursa (Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Boys; Individual Portraits; Children; Bursa, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Ottoman Writing
- Haldun in garment with belt. "To my dear Aunt Vangeli." 16.2 x 10.7 cm, 7 February 1901; 3482; Studio - Photographie Moriglioni, Bursa (Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Photographic Prints; Children; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Bursa, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Carpets/Rugs; Ottoman Writing; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Studio Photography
- Haldun, in garment with belt. "To my dear grandmother and my uncles". 16.2 x 10.7 cm, 7 February 1901; 3485; Studio - Photographie Moriglioni, Bursa (Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Bursa, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Carpets/Rugs; Ottoman Writing; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Children
- Woman in dress with embroidery. 16.5 x 10.5 cm, 7 January 1903; 3488; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Women; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Turkey; Individual Portraits; Ottoman Writing; Jewelry; Embroidery; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints
- Portrait of Sadun in dark jacket with belt. 16.4 x 10.4 cm, 24 December 1902; 3490; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Ottoman Writing; Children; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Boys; Hats; Turkey; Fezes/Tarbouches; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gloves
- Sema Sarim (?) in a print dress. 16.4 x 10.4 cm, 24 December 1902; 3491; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Ottoman Writing; Children; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople
- Portrait of Hasnun Galib in a light outfit, wearing a fez. 16.5 x 10.5 cm, 13 December 1902; 3492; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Painted Backdrops; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Children; Ottoman Writing; Furnishings; Istanbul, Turkey; Hats; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Individual Portraits; Boys
- Portrait of a soldier, holding rifle with bayonet. 18.2 x 12.5 cm, Unknown; 3493; Studio Fotografhane-i Osmani ve Aflam, Besiktas (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Photographic Prints; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Furnishings; Fezes/Tarbouches; Guns; Men; Painted Backdrops; Individual Portraits; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Military/Soldiers; Istanbul, Turkey; Weapons; Turkish Writing; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Facial Hair
- Woman in light-colored dress. 16.6 x 10.7 cm, 1903; 3504; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Women
- Woman with long hair standing in dark dress with buckled leather straps on her wrists. 16.2 x 10.1 cm, 1889; 3510; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Women; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey
- Man with mustache wearing a three-piece suit and a fez. 16.2 x 10.6 cm, 1889; 3513; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Men
- Man in long coat holding a cane and hat. 16.3 x 10.4 cm, 1889; 3514; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Gloves; Men; Canes/Walking Sticks; Hats; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Individual Portraits; Constantinople; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Albumen Prints; Jewelry; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair
- Girl in white dress with lace trim and a white bow in her hair. 16.4 x 10.8 cm, Undated; 3515; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Individual Portraits; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Constantinople; Children; Girls; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card
- Woman in dark dress with lace trim. 16.5 x 10.7 cm, 1888; 3516; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Women; Furnishings; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints
- Man in dark coat with a flower in his lapel. 16.4 x 10.6 cm, Undated; 3517; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Individual Portraits; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Men; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Facial Hair
- Man with mustache in suit with white bow tie and military medal on lapel. 16.5 x 10.5 cm, 11 November 1900; 3518; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Facial Hair; German Writing; Jewelry; Gloves; Books; Furnishings; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Bow Ties; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair
- Family portrait of a couple and their baby in a lace gown. 16.6 x 10.6 cm, April 1901; 3519; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Men; Women; Children; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; English Writing; Constantinople; Furnishings; Embroidery; Bow Ties; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- Three brothers and their sister. Same children as ref31. 16.7 x 10.7 cm, 1901; 3520; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Boys; Girls; Children; Group Portraits; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Furnishings; Albumen Prints; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Studio Photography
- Three brothers and their sister, standing in a row. 16.4 x 10.8 cm, 1900; 3521; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Children; Boys; Girls; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Constantinople; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Albumen Prints; Group Portraits
- Meur. & Mme Meissner Pacha and their daughter, Lucette. 16.5 x 10.5 cm, 1901; 3522; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Group Portraits; Studio Photography; Men; Women; Girls; Children; Furnishings; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Facial Hair; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Facial Hair
- Feridun Neset as a soldier. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, 18 May 1923; 3523; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Men; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Gloves; Hats; Uniforms; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Military/Soldiers; Studio Photography; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Ottoman Writing; French Writing; Constantinople; Medals/Insignia
- Soldier standing with a downcast gaze. İhtiyat Zabit Mektebi, Harbiye, Istanbul. 13.05 x 9.1 cm, 12 April 1912; 3524; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Uniforms; Hats; Swords/Knives; Books; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Weapons; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Military/Soldiers; Men; Schools/Education; Facial Hair
- Group portrait with Velid Ebuzziya. 8.9 x 13.8 cm, Undated; 3525; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Buildings; Architecture; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Canes/Walking Sticks; Bow Ties; Men; Istanbul, Turkey; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Streets/Roads; Cameras; Facial Hair; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
- Woman in black dress with black feathers. 13.1 x 8.1 cm, 9 September 1947; 3526; Studio Photo Abel, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Turkish Writing; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Jewelry; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Women
- Portrait of Mustafa Kemal. 13.9 x 9 cm, 1918; 3527; Studio Derounian Freres, Alep, Syrie (Aleppo, Syria) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Hats; Painted Backdrops; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Uniforms; Mustafa Kemal Ataturk, 1881-1938; Men; Aleppo, Syria; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Medals/Insignia
- Three men with two shisha (hookah) pipes. 14.9 x 11.9 cm, Undated; 3528; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Facial Hair; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Mirrors; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Facial Hair; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Men; Group Portraits; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Woman wearing hat, leaning on pillows. 16.5 x 10.5 cm, Undated; 3529; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Furnishings; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Hats; Women; Armenian Writing
- Armenian Patriarch Nerses Varjabedyan (1837-1884), sitting, wearing Armenian clerical vestments. 16.1 x 10.7 cm, Undated; 3530; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Men; Facial Hair; Turkish Writing; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Furnishings; Priests/Clergymen; Armenian Writing
- Two boys and one girl standing on a carpet, holding flowers. A souvenir from Mahmud Pertev Pasha. 16.7 x 10.9 cm, 18 March 1890; 3531; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Carpets/Rugs; Albumen Prints; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Girls; Boys; Ottoman Writing; Children; Pasha; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Group Portraits
- Girl and a boy standing in white gowns with palm fronds at their feet. 16.5 x 10.8 cm, 1892; 3532; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Painted Backdrops; Girls; Boys; Children; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Group Portraits
- Two girls and one boy standing on a carpet with a book on a table. 16.6 x 10.8 cm, Undated; 3533; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Boys; Girls; Books; Furnishings; Carpets/Rugs; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Children; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Group Portraits
- Kenan as a young boy in ornate dress. 16.5 x 10.8 cm, 1895; 3534; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Hats; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Carpets/Rugs; Painted Backdrops; Turkish Writing; Furnishings; Ottoman Writing; Books; Fezes/Tarbouches; Children; Boys; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card
- Two girls, one holding a basket of flowers and the other holding a stuffed bird, and one boy sitting on a tricycle. 16.6 x 10.9 cm, Undated; 3535; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Studio Photography; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Animals; Bicycles/Tricycles; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Painted Backdrops; Birds; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Boys; Girls; Children; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits
- Sarven and Iseda Dumentz as young girls, sitting in a rowboat. 19.8 x 15.3 cm, 20 June 1908; 3536; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder Oversize)
  French Writing; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Children; Water; Boats/Ships; Painted Backdrops; Girls; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Group Portraits
- Portrait of W.W. Peet, Esq. Writing, "Amerikan Bord Heyeti" stamp on back. 19.2 x 14.1 cm, 1900; 3537; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Oversize unknown container)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Turkish Writing; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Constantinople; Facial Hair; Men; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey
- Two girls in light colored gowns sitting on furniture. 16.2 x 10.6 cm, Undated; 3538; Studio Photo L'Aigle, Grand Rue de Pera 429, Constantinople (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Oversize unknown container)